Guide to the Office of Institutional Research, Yale University, Records and Reports
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Office of Institutional Research, Yale University, records and reports
1925-2014
RU 173
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
73.25
The records consist of reports, budgets, research materials, statistics, sample tests, and fact books.
Yale University. Office of Institutional Research
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 3-D (YRG 3-D), Records documenting academic support functions at Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
Access is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The Office of Institutional Research provides support and services for the provost, as well as for University committees affiliated with the provost. The Office of Institutional Research grew out of the Office of Educational Research, which originally reported to the Yale College dean's office. During the 1950s, it was influential in the creation of educational testing. During the 1960s the name of the office was changed to its current name. In 1978, the Office of Institutional Research was assigned to the provost. In addition to overseeing general administrative issues pertaining to the provost, the Office of Institutional Research is responsible for the coordination of standardized educational tests and for the creation and distribution of college questionnaires.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, budgets, research materials, statistics, sample tests, and fact books.
College students -- United States -- Statistics; Education, Higher -- Research; Educational statistics; Educational surveys; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Statistics; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Office of Institutional Research; Yale University. Office of the Provost
- Sample tests, circa 1925-1961; Accession 1978-A-018
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Sample tests
    - Cooperative Tests, by subject, 1932-1949 (Box 1)
    - Iowa Placement Tests, 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    - University of Chicago Tests, 1935-1950 (Box 1)
    - Misc. tests, alphabetical, undated (Box 2)
    - Achievement tests, social studies, undated (Box 2)
    - Achievement tests, scientific, undated (Box 2)
    - Aptitude tests, mechanical, undated (Box 2)
    - Aptitude tests, miscellaneous, 1950, undated (Box 2)
    - Aptitude tests, scientific, 1943, undated (Box 2)
    - Aptitude tests, spatial, undated (Box 2)
    - Aptitude tests, verbal, undated (Box 2)
    - Intelligence tests, undated (Box 3)
    - Interest tests, undated (Box 3)
    - Personality tests, undated (Box 3)
    - Personality tests, undated (Box 4)
    - Achievement tests, general, undated (Box 4)
    - Aptitude tests, general, 1948, undated (Box 4)
    - Misc. questionnaire, 1939, undated (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous tests, undated (Box 4)
    - Personnel report forms, undated (Box 4)
    - Y.U. School of Law, Legal Aptitude Test (LAT), 1941 (Box 5)
    - U.S. Armed Forces Institute Test, 1943 (Box 5)
    - Yale Educational Aptitude Test Battery (YEATB), 1946-1961 (Box 5)
    - C.E.E.B. Special Veterans Placement Test, undated (Box 5)
    - Machine scoring stencils, YEATB, ALT, 1946-1952 (Box 6)
    - Truncated III and IV, others, 1946-1952 (Box 6)
    - Truncated VII and VI, others, 1952 (Box 6)
    - YEATB booklets, packets, answer sheets, 1946-1952 (Box 6)
    - Various CEEB Tests, 1926-1929 (Box 6)
    - Univ. of Chicago Scholarship Exam, undated (Box 6)
    - Miller Analogies Answer Sheets, undated (Box 6)
    - Kuder Preference Record, 1953 (Box 6)
    - GRE, undated (Box 6)
    - American Council Psychological Examination, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Eight-year Study Materials - Tyler, undated (Box 7)
    - Various C.E.E.B. Tests, 1928-1944 (Box 7)
    - YEATB I-VII, 1936-1961 (Box 7)
    - YEATB, booklets, 1940-1951 (Box 8)
    - Y.U., School of Law (L.A.T.), booklets, 1941-1947 (Box 8)
    - Misc. secondary school tests, alphabetically, undated (Box 9)
    - Prep school and follow-up studies, 1937-1938 (Box 9)
    - Material for revision, undated (Box 9)
    - Answer keys, undated (Box 9)
    - Examiner's manual, 1938-1942 (Box 9)
    - Blank answer sheets, hand-scored, undated (Box 9)
    - Blank answer sheets, machine-scored, undated (Box 9)
    - Yale tests, by subject (YEATB), 1937, undated (Box 9)
    - Individual Profile Graphs (blank), by Classes, 1950-1965 (Box 10)
    - L.A,T., some grades and lists, by Classes, 1928-1956 (Box 10)
    - L.A.T. scoring stencils, 1938, undated (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous law tests, by form, undated (Box 10)
- Administrative records, 1963-1980; Accession 1980-A-014
  - 71M001: Sternberg, R.J. Is a Second Folder Reading Necessary?, 1970 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 71M002: Sternberg, R.J. Research of David McClelland., 1971 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 71R003: Sternberg, R.J. Notes on the Alumni Interview., 1971 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 71R004: Sternberg, R.J. Stepwise Multiple Regression Analysis of Final Action, Reader 1 Recommended Action, Reader 1 Academic and Personal Ratings (Class of 1974)., 1971 February 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 71M005: Sternberg, R.J. Applicant Information Duplication., 1971 February 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 71M006: Hoskins, J.H. Undergraduate Admissions, 1971 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 71R007: Research Committee: Notes Toward Program Formulation., 1971 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 71R008: OIR (Series). Yale College Fall Term Grades, 1970-1971., 1971 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 71M009: Undergraduate Admissions Research Committee. Report of the Undergraduate Admissions Research Committee., 1971 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 71RO10: Sternberg, R.J. The Formulation and Execution of Admissions Policy in Highly Selective Colleges. [not included], 1971 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 71RO11: Sternberg, R.J. Relationship of Staff Interview Ratings to other Admissions Indices., 1971 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 71R012: Sternberg, R.J. Relationship of Categorization to Admission Predictors. Undergraduate Admissions Research Committee. Research in Undergraduate Admissions., 1971 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 71R013: Sternberg, R.J. Comparison between the Staff Interview Personal Rating and ASC Rating., 1971 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 71R014: Sternberg, R.J. Relationship of ASC Ratings to Other Admissions Criteria., 1971 June 23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 71R015: OIR (Series). Yale College Spring Term Grades, 1970-1971., 1971 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 71R016: Sternberg, R.J. A Decision Rule to Categorize Yale College Applicants., 1971 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 71R017: Sternberg, R.J. Extraction of Research Relevant Data from ADS Admissions Master File (Revised)., 1971 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 71M018: Sternberg, R.J. Changes in SAT Scores and Other Admissions Ratings, and the Rolling Decision Plan., 1971 August 31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 71M0I9: Sternberg, R.J. Comparative Expectancies of Admission for Yale Affiliates and Non-affiliates., 1971 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 71R020: OIR. Profile of the Yale College Class of 1975., 1971 September 15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 71R021: Sternberg, R.J. A Decision Rule to Facilitate the Undergraduate Admissions Process. [lacking], 1971 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 71M022: Sternberg, R.J. Performance of the Admissions Committee under Rolling Decision and the Decision Rule (First Meeting)., 1971 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 71R023: Jackson, R., and Ho~kins, J.H. Yale College Class of 1975: Applicants Admitted who Withdrew to Other Schools., 1971 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 71M024: Sternberg, R.J. Computer Inspection of Senior Year Application Data., 1971 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 71R025: Sternberg, R.J. A Proposal for a Study of College Admissions i.n the United States with Particular Reference to Admissions at Yale., 1971 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 71M026: Sternberg, R.J. Notes and Further Notes on Elga Wasserman's Reply to Research Bulletin #1, 1971 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 71M027: Sternberg,. R.J. Predictability of Motivated Performance in Students., 1971 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 71M028: Sternberg, R.J. Alumni Affairs: Report of the Commission on The Role -of Alumni in Admissions., 1971 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 71M029: Hoskins, J.R. Operating Bob Sternberg's Rule., 1971 October 6 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 72M001: Sternberg, R.J. Performance of the Admissions Committee under Rolling Decision and the Decision Rule (Second Meeting)., 1972 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 72M002: OIR. Yale Sons and Daughters in Freshman Classes, 1924 -, 1972 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 72M003: Jackson, R. Children of Alumni of Undergraduate Schools., 1972 January 26 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 72R004: Sternberg, R.J., and Morrison, J. Modified Science Distinction., 1972 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 72M005: Sternberg, R.J. Modified Science Distinction and the Cooley Study. Abstract of "Career Development of Scientists: An Overlapping Longitudinal Study"., 1972 February 11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 72R006: Sternberg, R.J.- Correlational Patterns in -Reader Ratings and Committee Action Patterns over the Past Three Years: Supplement to the Final Report on Rolling Decision., 1972 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 72R007: Spector, K.K. Potential for Increased Numbers of Women Faculty at Yale., 1972 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 72R008: Sternberg, R.J. Performance of the Admissions Committee under Rolling Decision and the Decision Rule - Final Report., 1972 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 72R009: Powell, P.M., and Jackman, J.D. Research in Undergraduate Admissions. A Proposal to Study Criteria of Undergraduate Performance, and the Relationship of these to Measures by which Undergraduates are Selected for Admission to Yale College (12-13-71, revised 02-23-72), 1972 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 72R010: Jackson, R. Comparative Expectancies of Admission for Yale Affiliates and Non-Affiliates., 1972 February 23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 72M011: Inzunza, F. Review of Admit-Withdraws from Yale College Class of 1975 who were Members of Minority Groups. [not included], 1972 February 29 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 72R012: OIR (Series). Yale College Fall Term Grades, 1971-1972., 1972 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 72M013: Spector, K.K. Proportion of Women: FAS to Total Ph.D. Recipients., 1972 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 72R014: OIR (Series). The Yale College Class of 1971:. Its Postgraduation Plans., 1972 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 72M015: Jackson, R. Research Relating to Admission of Good Science Prospects., 1972 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 72R016: OIR. Enrollment, Grade Distribution, and Appointment Status of Teachers in College Seminars, 1970-71., 1972 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 72M017: Hoskins, J.R. How Many Students to Net $3,500,000?, 1972 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 72M018: OIR. Revision of Memo dated 04-14-72 - FAS Women., 1972 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 72R019: Hoskins, J.H. Student Evaluation of Teaching., 1972 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 72R020: Burnham, P.S. and Hewitt, B.A. "The Rock Stands, Mr. Noyes." College Board Review, 1972, §,l, 25-29., Spring, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 72R021: Burnham, P.S. and Hewitt, B.A. Determining vocational characteristics vs. predicting membership: A follow-up of male college graduates. J. -of Psychology, 1972, 81, 73-84., 1972 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 72M022: Jackson, R. Response to Questions on Calendar Change by Applicants to the Class of 1976 who were Admitted and who Withdrew to Other Schools., 1972 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 72M023: Jackson, R. Class of 1976 SAT Distributions., 1972 September 5 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 72M024: (See 72M025), 1972 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 72M025: Hoskins, J.H. Courses, Sections, and Course Enrollments in Yale College: 1950-51; 1961-62; 1971-72 •., 1972 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 72M026: Hoskins, J.H. Census of Yale Employees on -December 31, 1971., 1972 September 15 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 72R027: Sternberg, R.J. Statistical Evaluation of the Modified Science Distinction Program., 1972 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 72R028: OIR (Series). Yale College Spring Term Grades, 1971-1972., 1972 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 72R029: Hackman, J.D., Holford, M.H., Hoskins, J., Jackson, R., Powell, P., and Taber, T. -College Criteria Study: Prestudy Report No.1., 1972 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 72R030: Hoskins, J.H. Criteria of College Success., 1972 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 72R031: Taber, T. and Hackman, J.D. College Criteria Study. A proposal for further study of operational criteria used to distinguish successful college undergraduates from other undergraduate students., 1972 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 72R032: Berg, D.N. Interview: The Yale Criteria Study F'ollow-up Content and Process., 1972 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 72M033: Task Force on Student and Course Records: Class of 1973., 1972 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 72M034: OIR. Fall 1972 Compliance Report,. Title IV, Civil Rights Act of 1964., 1972 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 73M001: Hoskins, J.H. Music and Art: 1962-63. Undergraduate Registrations in Fall 1972, 1971~72, 1970-71, 1973 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 73M002: Hoskins, J.H. Admit-Withdraws to 69 Most Selective Colleges by Cross-Application Groups (1971-1976)., 1973 January 24 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 73R003: Taber, T. and Hackman, J.D. Criteria of College Success: Preliminary Outline to Exxon Foundation., 1973 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 73R004: OIR (Series). The Yale College Class of 1972: Its Postgraduation Plans., 1973 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 73M005: Hoskins, J.H. Schools with Trimester Schedules., 1973 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 73R006: Hoskins, J.R. Criteria of Success in Yale College., 1973 April 22 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 73R007: OIR (Series). Yale College Fall Term Grades, 1972-1973., 1973 March 21 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 73R008: Hansen, C. The Yale Experience., 1973 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 73R009: Hoskins, J.H. Enrollment, Housing and the Summer Term., 1973 June 19 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 73R010: Hackman, J.D. College Criteria Study. Pre-study Report #2: Admissions Scores of Nominees., 1973 July 6 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 73R011: Hackman, J.D. College Criteria Study. Pre-study Report #3: The Use of Criterion Categories., 1973 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 73R012: Hackman; J.D., Taber, T., and Holford, lot. College Criteria Study. Prestudy Report #4: Refining The Criterion Categories., 1973 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 73R013: Report removed from file permanently., Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 73R014: OIR. Athletes and non-athletes in the Yale Classes of 1958, 1962, 1967, and 1971., 1973 August 8 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 73R015: OIR (Series). Yale College Spring Term Grades, 1972-1973., 1973 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 73R016: OIR. Yale students enrolled in summer courses in 1973., 1973 October 10 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 73R017: OIR. OIR Admissions tape documentation for ADM 73, 74, 75, 76, 77, 78., 1973 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 73R018: OIR (Series). The Yale College Class of 1973: Its Post-graduation Plans., 1973 September 12 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 73R019: Suttle, J.L. and Hoskins, J.H. Attendance Patterns and Graduation Credits for the Yale College Class of 1973., 1973 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 74R001: Hoskins, J. and Suttle, J.L. Minority Students: Relationship of Tests and Grades., 1974 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 74R002: OIR (Series). Yale College Fall Term Grades, 1973-1974., 1974 April 23 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 74R003: Hoskins, J.H. and Suttle, J.L. English Courses Taken and Grades Earned by Freshmen in Yale College Classes of 1973 and 1974., 1974 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 74R004: OIR. Summary of (Highest) SAT Scores: Matriculants to Classes 1973-1977, 1974 January 29 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 74R005: OIR (Series). Yale College Spring Term Grades, 1973-1974. [lacking], 1974 July 1 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 74R006: OIR. Class Scheduling--Summer Term 1975., 1974 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 74R007: Hansen, J.S. College Criteria Study at Yale: Report on Multiple Nominees., 1974 October 10 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 74R008: Suttle, J.L. Evaluation of the Summer Term: A Preliminary Research Proposal., 1974 June 3 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 74R009: Suttle, J.L. April 1974 Summer Term Survey: Final Report., 1974 July 3 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 74R010: Suttle, J.L. Enrollment, Admissions, and the Summer Term: A Report on the Development and Use of an Enrollment Planning Model for Yale College., 1974 December 1 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 74R011: Hackman, J.D. and Hoskins, J.H. Dimensions of Student Performance in Yale College: A First Report of the College Criteria Study, 1974 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 74R012: Suttle, J.L. Procedures and Applications for the Statistical Analysis of Yale College Admissions Data., 1974 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 74R013: Hansen, J.S. Yale Criteria Study follow-up., 1974 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 75R001: Levin, N.B. Completion of HEGIS and Title IX Forms Using SPSS., 1975 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 75R002: OIR (Series). Yale College Fall Term Grades, 1974-1975., 1975 February 15 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 75R003: OIR. Biannual Report on Yale College Grades, Fall 1974-1975., 1975 April 2 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 75R004: Hoskins, J.H. Notes for Evaluation of the Office of Institutional Research 1971-1975., 1975 April 15 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 75R005: Hoskins, J.H. Achievement Tests of Applicants to the Class of 1978., 1975 September 16 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 75R006: OIR (Series). The Yale College Class of 1974: Its Postgraduation Plans., 1975 May 1 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 75R007: OIR. Biannual Report on Yale College Grades, Spring 1974-1975., 1975 January 7 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 75R008: OIR (Series). Yale College Spring Term Grades, 1974-1975., 1975 January 7 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 75R009: Hackman, J.D. Patterns of Successful Performance in Yale College: A Second Report of the College Criteria Study., 1975 August 28 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - 75R010: Hackman, J.D. Relationship of Success Types to Quantified Admissions Variables: Addendum to the Second Report of the College Criteria Study., 1975 August 1 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - 75R011: Hackman, J.D. Patterns of Unsuccessful Performance in Yale College: A Third Report of the College Criteria Study., 1975 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - 75R012: Hackman, J.D. Relationship of Unsuccessful Types to Quantified Admissions Variables: Addendum to the Third Report of the College Criteria Study., 1975 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - 75R013: Removed from file permanently., Undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - 75R014: Hackman, J.D. Relationships of the 7 Success Types With Additional Admissions and Background Variables., 1975 November 1 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - 75R015: Averill, R.F. and Suttle, J.L. A model for university enrollment planning. Socia-Economic Planning Sciences, 1975, 2, 257-261., 1975 November 1 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - 76R001: Hackman, J.D. The Yale Community Looks at Students: Notes from the College Criteria Study about the Undergraduate Experience., 1976 January 1 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - 76R002: Haclanan, J.D. and Taber, T. D. Comparing Differential Conceptions of Student Success Among the Yale College Community. [not included], 1976 February 1 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - 76R003: Suttle, J.L. Current Status of Student Cohorts and Data Files., 1976 February 2 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - 76R004: Taber, T.D. and Hackman, J.D. "Dimensions of undergraduate college performance." Journal of Applied Psychology, 1976, 61: 546-558., 1976 February 1 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - 76R005: Hackman, J.D. and Johnson, P. Yale College Freshmen: How Well Do They Write? Abstracted in Resources in Education, Educational Resources Information Clearinghouse, December, 1977., 1976 August 1 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - 76R006: OIR. Contributing History of Yale Alumni., 1976 March 1 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - 76R007: Hackman, J.D. and Taber, T.D. Typologies of Student Success and Nonsuccess Based on the College Criteria Questionnaire., 1976 July 1 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - 76R008: OIR (Series). Yale College Fall Term Grades,1975-1976., 1976 August 1 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - 76R009: OIR (Series). Yale College Spring Term Grades,1975-1976., 1976 August 1 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - 76R010: Hoskins, J.R. FTE Faculty and Department "Teaching Loads: FAS 1974-75 and 1975-76., 1976 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - 76R011: Suttle, J.L. Over-enrollment in Yale College: Its Sources and Solution., 1976 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - 76R012: OIR (Series). The Yale College Class of 1975: Its Current Activities., 1976 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - 76R013: Suttle, J.L. The Yale College Summer Term: A Statistical Summary of the First Two Years., 1976 November 1 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - 76R014: Suttle, J.L. Coping With the Summer Term., 1976 April 1 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - 77R001: Hoskins, J.H. An Introduction to the Yale College Student Registration System., 1977 March 1 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - 77R002: OIR (Series). Yale College Fall Term Grades, 1976-1977., 1977 June 1 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - 77R003: OIR (Series). Yale College Spring Term Grades. 1976-1977., 1977 August 1 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - 77R004: Hackman, J.D. and Taber, T.D. A Profile of the Multiple Evaluating Environments Within a College. Paper presented at the April, 1977, Annual Meeting of the American Educational Research-Association. Abstracted in Resourses in Education, Educational Resources Information Clearinghouse, August, 1977., 1977 April 1 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - 77R005: Suttle, J.L. Minority Admissions and Performance A Statistical Profile., 1977 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - 77R006: Hackman, J.D. and Johnson, P. How Well Do Freshmen Write? Implications for Placement and Pedagogy. College and University. Fall, 1997., 1977 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - 77R007: Johnson, P. and Hackman, J.D., The Yale Average: On, After Competence. College Composition and Communication, October 1977., 1977 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - 77R008: Suttle, J.L. OIR Annual Report for 1976-1977., 1977 September 9 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - 77R009: Suttle, J.L. Yale College Summer Programs for Minority Students from Other Schools; Soma Notes Toward an Evalutation., 1977 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - 77R010: Suttle, J.L. The Yale College Summer Term: A Statistical Summary of the First Three Years. [lacking], 1977 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - 77R011: OIR (Series). The Yale College Class of 1976: Its Current Activities, 1977 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - 77R012: Goldin, J .R. Trends in Alumni Giving. (Draft. Replaced by 78R018), 1977 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - 77R013: Suttle, J.L., Hackman, J.D. and Goldin, J,R. Financial Aid at Yale: Policies, Practices, and Expenditures (Draft), 1977 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - 77R014: Goldin, J .R. Placement in introductory Chemistry Courses., 1977 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - 77R015: Suttle, J.L., Temporary Incompletes in Yale College., 1977 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - 77R016: Hackman, J.D., Counting Students in Yale University., 1977 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - 77R017: Goldin, J.R., Alumni Sons and Daughers in Yale College., 1977 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - 78ROOl: Hackman, J.D., Attrition in Yale College., 1978 January 11 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - 78R002: Suttle, J.L., Graduation and Attrition Rates in Yale College: Fall 1997 Entrollment Status Reports., 1978 January 1 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - 78R003: OIR. Majors in Yale College for the Classes of 1961 to 1978. [lacking], 1978 January 1 (Box 4, Folder 64)